我刚拿到教师评鉴表 你们听这个学生写的
I got my teacher evaluations. Look what this student wrote.
“我爱盖勒博士的课” “令人大呼过瘾”
"I loved Dr. Geller's class. Mind-blowing lectures.
“盖勒博士” “您是古生物学系的猛男”
You are definitely the hottie of the Paleontology Department."
古生物学系的猛男们 做成月历一定热卖
"Hotties of Paleontology." There's a big-selling calendar.
那是谁写的？
-Who wrote it?
我也想知道 但评鉴表是匿名的
-The evaluations are all anonymous.
期末考考卷还在吗？ 在啊
-You have their exams? -Yeah.
你可以拿考卷来对笔迹 就知道仰慕者是谁了
You could just match the handwriting and there's your admirer.
只要和女生有关 他就成了大天才（电影《雨人）》
A hot girl's at stake and he's Rain Man.
等等，为何确定是个女生？
Wait a minute. Why are we so sure that this is a girl?
是女生
It's a girl!
总之没错 因为我是老师，她是学生
But it wouldn't matter.Because I'm a teacher. She's a student.
校规说不行？
-It's illegal?
没有，但是会有争议 了解
-It's frowned upon.
而且年龄差那么多
-And there's a big age gap.
你就这么想，等你90岁…
-When you're 90..
我知道，我90她就80 感觉就差不多了
I know,she'll be 80 and it won't seem like such a big difference.
我不是要说这个
That's not what I was gonna say.
我是说等你90岁
When you're 90,
还能拥有跟小妹妹恋爱的回忆
you'll still have the memory of being with a 20-year-old.
本集播出：“师生恋”
The One Where Ross Dates A Student
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
寇妮考克斯阿奎特
丽莎库卓
麦特勒布兰
马修派瑞
大卫修蒙
莫妮卡…
-Monica..?
我不知道 好吧
-I don't know.
钱德
Chandler
你知道你那个当上导演的大学同学吗？
You know your college friend who became a movie director?
知道，黛娜基史东 我们一起修动作课
Oh yeah,Dana Keystone. She was in my movement class.
什么是动作课？
-What's a movement class?
钱德在假装他没修过哑剧
-He's pretending he didn't take mime.
总之她要导艾尔帕西诺的新片
She's directing a new Al Pacino movie.
你得帮我争取试镜
You gotta get me an audition.
我不知道，我们10年没联络了
I haven't talked to her in 10 years.
不，求求你，就当我欠你的
Please,Chandler,I would owe you so much.
你本来就欠我的
You do owe me so much.
你欠我3千4百… 老兄
You owe me 3400..Hey,hey,dude.
你干嘛转移话题？ 什么
Why you changing the subject? What?
你打不打电话？
-Will you make the call?
好吧，我试试看
-Okay,I'll try.
万岁！谢了，你最好了
Thanks.
试镜是星期四截止
Last auditions are Thursday,
我星期四之前得过去 记得星期四就对了，你记得吗
so I gotta get in by Thursday.Remember Thursday. Remember Thursday?
星期二吗？
Yeah,so Tuesday?
是星期四
Thursday!
你如果记不住就记是第三天
Just think of it like this: The third day.
星期一，一天，星期二，二天
Monday,one day.Tuesday,two day.
星期三，三天？ 哪一天？星期四
Wednesday... When day,what day?Thursday!
第三天，好吗？
The third day,okay?
谢谢你 不客气
-Thank you. -Okay.
莫妮卡… 她不知道
-Hey,Monica..? -She doesn't know.
莫妮卡，我要听留言 你在厕所里想到这个？
-I'm gonna check my messages. -You thought of that in there?
当然，生理反应 她想知道还有谁在做同样的事
Nature called. She wants to see who else did.
喂？
Hello?
瑞秋
Rachel.
我们家有人，快报警
Someone's in our apartment. Call the cops!
你在用电话
You're on the phone!
天哪…天哪，谢谢你
-Oh,my God! -What?Oh,my God! Thank you!
是消防队，家里失火了
There was a fire at our place.
天哪，有多严重？
-Oh,my God! How bad was it?
他没说，但失火总是不太妙
-It was a fire,I'm guessing not good.
快走吧 快点
-Come on,we gotta go! -Yeah,come on.
笑什么笑？有什么好笑的？
What are you smiling about? What is so funny？
我要应征的角色是消防队员 这真是天意
The part I want to audition for is a fireman. This is so meant to be!
你这学期的成绩给得很大方喔
You were very generous with your grades this semester.
盖勒教授？ 是的
-Professor Geller? -Yeah?
我很喜欢你的课
-I really enjoyed your class.
谢谢你，非常感谢
-Oh,thank you. Thanks very much.
不好意思，说你是猛男
I'm a little embarrassed about calling you a hottie.
那是你？ 对，我后来觉得怪怪的
-That was you? -Yeah.I felt a little weird about it.
你是老师，我是学生
You're a teacher. I'm a student.
但或许你愿意和我约会？
Want to go out sometime?
这样恐怕不太好
That's not the best idea.
我想说学期结束 你就不是我的老师了
Oh,because I was thinking,the semester's over.You're not my teacher anymore.
什么时候？
What time?
当我没说，你已经给我A了
Oh,you know what? Forget it.I see you already gave me an A.
了解 开玩笑的
-Gotcha. -I'm kidding! God!
说真的，什么时候？
So seriously,what time?
借过，借过
Coming through. Coming through.
你好
Oh! Hello. Hi.
不对，借过
Right. Coming through!
还好嘛 灾情主要集中在卧房
Okay. It's not so bad.Most of the damage was contained to the bedrooms.
老兄 这星期四可以跟你借制服吗？
Hey,buddy,think I could borrow your uniform this Thursday?
什么？ 乔伊，人家在忙
-Excuse me? -Joey! He's working.
你穿一定很帅
You would look good in that.
灾情如何？ 很惨，非常惨
Oh,how bad is it?It's really bad.
只有一个斧头没被烧到 我根本不记得有买过
The only thing that isn't burned is an ax,which I do not remember buying.
瑞秋你呢？ 东西都烧光了，床铺，衣服
-How's your room? -Everything's ruined.My bed,my clothes.
你看我最喜欢的蓝毛衣 那不是我的吗？
Look at my favorite sweater.Isn't that mine?
好，我对你的损失深感遗撼
Fine. I'm sorry for your loss.
这里暂时不能住人 你们有地方去吗？
You won't be able to live here for a while. You have a place to stay?
好，你给我听着 我现在没心情被搭讪
Okay,look,pal...I am not in the mood to be hit on right now.
不过要是你给我电话 我改天会打给你
But if you give me your number,I'll call you sometime.
她们可以跟我们住
Yes,they can stay with us.
请问起火原因是什么，消防员先生？
Do you know what started the fire,Mr. Fireman?
你们有人抽烟吗？
Well,do either of you smoke?
没有，不过现在来一根也好
No. But yeah,I could use one now. Thanks.
不是，你们有人点蜡烛烧香吗
-Do you light candles,burn incense?
有，我常点，我很喜欢
-I do all the time. I love them!
天哪，是我害的 我把房子给烧了
Oh,my God,I did it! It's me,it's me! I burned down the house!
菲比，别激动 没有必要怪谁，好吗？
Okay,Phoebe,calm down. There's no need to place blame. Okay?
我警告过她
I warned her about those candles.
能聊聊真好，居然这么久了
I can't believe how long it's been.
钱德，是不是…
Hey,Chandler,is that..?
太好了，恭喜你
-Oh,that's great,good for you.
是不是可以…
-So,is it..?
好，我们可以见个面…
Okay. So,yeah,maybe we can get together...
你等我一下…怎样？
Hold on for one second.What?
等你讲完，要不要叫披萨？
Do you want to get a pizza later?
我回来了
Hi,I'm back.
听起来不错 好，就这么决定…好，再见
Yeah,that sounds great. We'll do it then. Okay,bye.
我什么时候试镜？ 我知道是星期四，但是几点？
When's my audition? I know it's Thursday,but what time?
我们没聊到那个 我带她去喝咖啡时再说
Hi. We didn't get to it.I'm taking her to coffee. We'll do it then.
你要跟这个女生约会？
Now you're going on a date with this girl?
这不是约会，我们失去联系10年了
I haven't talked to her in 10 years.
总不能一通电话过去 就要人家帮忙
You can't just call up and ask somebody for a favor.
要讲人情世故，花点时间客套
There are rules,you know? You gotta put in some time.
没错，对不起 你又不是去见旧情人
Right,I'm sorry.It's not like she's an ex-girlfriend.
我们只约过一次会
We only went out once.
你跟她交往过？
You dated her?!
一次也没有
Not once.
干脆我也去找个前男友 来帮乔伊的忙
Why don't I just go out with an ex,you know,and do Joey a favor?
想帮乔伊的忙就跟乔伊约会
You want to do Joey a favor? Maybe you go out with Joey.
真好，我朋友乔伊也在电影圈
That's great. My friend Joey's in the movie business.
你猜我那天遇见谁？豪伊
You know who I ran into from school? Howie.
我的朋友叫乔伊
My friend's name is Joey.
豪伊在当剪接师
Apparently,Howie's editing now.
他打来问能不能剪我的新片
Yeah,he calls me up and asks me if he can edit my new movie.
你相信吗？我们10年没联络 他居然来找我帮忙
Can you believe that?You know,I haven't spoken to him in 10 years...and he asks me for a favor?
我一向很讨厌那家伙
Yeah,I've always hated that Howie.
连声好都没问 连先喝杯咖啡都没有
No "How you doing?"Man,I mean,not even a cup of coffee first.
好大胆 就是啊
-The nerve. -Yeah.
续杯吗？
Refill?
事出突然，抱歉房里一团乱
This is last-minute,so I want to apologize for the mess.
天哪
Oh,my God!
我住的时候绝对不是这样 我知道
It sure didn't look this way when I lived here.I know!
问题是这里只能睡一个人 另一个人得去住乔伊家
But there's only room for one,so one of you will have to stay at Joey's.
既然火算是我放的 你就睡这里吧
Since the fire was kind of my fault,you should get to stay here.
谁也没有错，那是个意外
Hey,hey,now. This was no one's fault. It was an accident.
不，是我害的，你应该睡这里 好吧
It was my fault. You should get the nice room.Okay!
瑞秋，你是莫妮卡旅店的首位贵客
You're the first guest at "Hotel Monica."
你得告诉我早餐想吃什么蛋 我打算端到床上给你
Just tell me how you like your eggs.I thought I'd bring them to you in bed.
你吃了这么多苦 就是啊
-You've been through so much. -I have.
这是我放披萨的地方
This right here is where I keep the pizza.
纸巾在那里
And that's where the napkin is.
什么味道？ 就是啊
-What's that smell? -I know! I don't...
拜托，那么大一个班 你根本没有注意到我
Oh,please,it was such a big class. You never even noticed me.
当然有，你坐在“睡鬼”旁边 谁？
What? Of course I did. You sat next to "Sleepy Sleeperson."Who?
我记不住全班的名字 就取绰号代替
Oh. I had trouble remembering names,so I came up with nicknames.
像你的另一边是“发臭冯棕色上衣”
The guy on the other side of you was "Smelly Von Brown Shirt."
没错
Oh,yeah.
你有帮我取绰号吗？ 没有
-So did you have a nickname for me? -No. No.
你有，是什么？
Yes,you did. What was it?
“漂亮美丽”
"Cutie McPretty."
真好
Oh,that's so sweet!
说真的，今晚真的很开心
Listen,I gotta tell you,I'm having a great time.
你之前说师生约会很奇怪
You said it might be weird,the whole student/teacher thing?
其实我也有同感 结果不会，一点也不会
And to be frank,I thought it would be too.But it's not. I mean,it's not at all.
盖勒博士 伯特
-Dr. Geller! -Burt!
你昨晚睡得好吗？
-Did you sleep well last night?
很好，莫妮卡很贴心，还在我的枕头上 放了一小片薄荷
-I did.Monica was so sweet. She left a little mint on my pillow.
你猜乔伊在我枕头上放什么？
Know what Joey left on my pillow?
什么？ 口香糖
Gum.
找到起火原因了
-We determined the cause of the fire.
我知道，是我的蜡烛害的
-I know. It was my candle,my candle!
不是，浴室有个电器没拔掉 好像是卷发器
No,there was an appliance left on. It looks like a curling iron.
我没在用卷发器 总有人在用
-I don't use a curling iron. -Someone does.
别看我，我的头发是直的 直的直的直的
Don't look at me,my hair's straight. Straight,straight,straight.
也可能是直发夹
-It could've been a hair straightener. -Oh.
披萨都放这里
This is where I keep the pizza.
纸巾呢？
And.. Hey,where'd the napkin go?
什么味道？是臭掉的虾吗？
What is that?Is that old shrimp?
应该是喔
I think it is!
这样，可不能让贵客眼睛疲劳
I wouldn't want my best guest to strain her eyes.
谢谢莫妮卡
Thanks,Monica.
你怕那个味道吗？
-Does that smell bother you?
乔伊家的味道？这里又闻不到
-From Joey's?I can hardly smell it over here.
闻得到就说 我可以烤个派把它盖过去
Well,you let me know if you can. I can bake a pie to cover it.
有点闻得到，烤个派吧 好
-I can smell it a little,bake a pie. -Okay.
喂？  请稍候
Hello?One minute,please.
火场调查员找你
It's the fire inspector.
喂？我是菲比
Hello? Yeah,this is Phoebe.
是吗？
Really?
是的，所以直发夹不是起火点
Yeah,so it turns out that it wasn't the hair straightener...that started the fire.
不，是蜡烛 把蜡烛点着不管实在不太好
No,no. It was the candles.Yeah. It's very not good leaving candles unattended.
消防学校最先教的事情之一…
In fact,one of the first things they teach you in fire school is...
好，我该挂了
okay,well I have to go now.
我们玩得好开心，她好棒
We had such a great time. She's incredible.
我以为年龄会造成问题 结果一点也不会
I thought the age difference might be a problem,but it wasn't.
伊丽莎白非常成熟
Elizabeth is very mature for her age.
有些人就是不懂
A concept lost on some people.
所以师生可以约会
It's okay to date a student?
也不是，技术上没触犯校规 但是会受争议
Well,not really. Technically,it's not against the rules.
尤其是我们昨晚遇见的教授“法官冯比你高尚”
But it's frowned upon,especially by the professor we saw last night:"Judgy Von Holier-than-thou."
罗斯，小心一点 别被叫成“和学生乱搞”教授
You don't want to get a reputation as "Professor McNails-his-students."
我该怎么办？
-Yeah. What should I do?
很简单，什么比较重要？ 别人的看法还是你的感觉？
-Well,it seems pretty clear.What's more important? What people think or how you feel?
你得忠于你的心
-You gotta follow your heart.
乔伊，你说得真好
-Joey,that's so sweet.
你跟黛娜谈得怎样？ 我星期四该不该空出时间来？
-Hi. -Hey! So how'd it go with Dana?Any reason I should leave a block of time open? Say,Thursday?
我说不出口 你说不出口？
-I couldn't do it. -You couldn't do it?
别急，我需要更多时间 我们晚上要吃饭
I need more time. We're going to dinner.
什么？你还要跟她出去
You're going out with her again?
跟谁出去？ 大学的黛娜基史东
-Going out with who? -Dana Keystone,from college.
她不是…
Oh,yeah. Wasn't she...?
那是黛娜卡普林
No,that was Dana Kaplan.
乔伊，你根本不知道是谁 随便啦
-Joey,you didn't even know her! -Yeah,whatever.
故事真的好棒，好错综复杂
Great story again.The yarns that you weave!
我该走了
You know,actually,I should get going.
留下来，你应该留下来
Oh,no,no,stay! Because you should stay.
我真的很受宠若惊 但是我对你没感觉
Oh,I am really flattered.But I just... I don't feel that way about you.
不，我不是…不是
Oh,no,no. That's not..
钱德，对不起 你人很好，我也不想伤害你
I'm sorry,Chandler. You know,you're such a sweet guy...and I don't want to hurt you.
真想设法让你好过一点 不…真的吗？
I wish I could do something to make you feel better.No.. Really?
当然
Of course.
我真是太伤心了，我…
Well,it just hurts so bad,I...
对不起
Oh,I'm sorry.
或许你可以做一件事 什么事？你尽管说
-Maybe there is one thing you can do. -What? Anything. Anything.
我是刚刚才想到的
Well,I mean,this is just off the top of my head now.
我有个朋友，演员朋友 他要是知道一定会杀了我
But I have this friend.. This actor friend.He would kill me if he knew that I was doing this.
但你可不可能让他去试镜 就星期四吧？
But...would it be possible for him to audition for your movie on Thursday?
没问题
Absolutely.
但是我让你的朋友来试镜 真的能让你好过一点？
But...you'd really feel better if your friend could audition for my movie?
这是我的心愿，再见
The heart wants what it wants. Bye.
怎么样啊？ 这5分钟都没什么变化
Hey! How's it going?Well,not much has changed in the last five minutes.
其实有，我烤了饼干
Yes,it has. I made cookies!
不了，我还在消化你做的薯片
I'm still full from your homemade potato chips.
但是饼干应该刚烤好就趁热吃
But you should eat them now,because they're hot from the oven.
好 但不是在这里
Okay.But not in here!
床上不能吃饼干，不能掉屑屑
Can't eat them in bed,remember? No crumbies!
好，我马上出去 好
Oh. Okay,I'll be out in a second.Okay.
你在干什么？ 门不能锁对吧？
-What are you doing? -This doesn't lock,does it?
乔伊，对不起
-Oh! Joey,I'm sorry.
没关系，别在意
-It's all right,don't worry about it.
但是你看，会有印子
But look! That's gonna leave a stain.
瑞秋，没关系，这是乔伊家
Rach,hey,it's fine. You're at Joey's.
真的吗？ 当然，你看
-Really? -Yeah,look.
我没有这样吃过东西 我知道
-I've never lived like this before. -I know.
别浪费了，这是食物
Well,don't waste it. I mean,it's still food.
接着要干嘛？要不要去喝酒？
What do you want to do now? Want to get a drink?
我不行
I can't.
你要念书？ 不是，我还没满21岁
-Oh,you have some studying to do? -No,I have some turning 21 to do.
我以前念大学时，我们都…
You know,I remember when I was in college,we used to..
你干什么？ 没事，我只是觉得好舒服
-What are you doing? -Nothing,I'm so comfortable with you.
你怕被别人看见？
Do you not want to be seen with me?
什么？当然不是 他们走了吗？
No,of course I do. Are they gone?
他们还在，不过我要走了 什么？等一下
No,they're still here. But I think I'm about to leave.What? No,no,wait,wait..
你说得对，这样太蠢了 管别人怎么想
You're right,this is stupid. Who cares what people think?
我们情投意合，对吧？ 这样并没有错
I mean,we like each other,right?There's nothing wrong with that.
走吧
Come on.
伯特，莉蒂亚，梅尔
Burt. Lydia. Mel.
这位是伊丽莎白
-This is Elizabeth. -Hi.
你是不是有在修我的大众文化？
Aren't you in my popular culture class?
没错，伊丽莎白是学生 我们在交往
That's right,Lydia. Elizabeth is a student.And we're dating
你们可以皱眉摇头 但我们不会再躲了
And you may frown upon that but...we're not gonna hide it anymore.
你肯定要被解聘了
You are so fired.
什么？
-What?
你会被解聘 跟学生交往是违规的
-They'll fire you.You can't date her. It's against the rules.
真的？不只是受争议？
Really? It's not just frowned upon?
我最喜欢乔伊家了
I love it at Joey's!
漂亮 谢谢
-Nice! -Thanks.
你星期四有事吗？
So you busy Thursday?
真好笑，不晓得你记不记得 我的试镜就是星期四
Oh,very funny. Remember? My audition was supposed to be Thursday.
你帮我争取到了？来抱抱
You got me the audition? Let's hug it up!
要是你入选还得了
Okay,okay! What are you gonna do to me if you get the part?
我有事要找你
-Hey. -Hi.Yeah,okay,I need to talk to you.
我知道他们说直发夹是起火点 但我也有责任
I know they said the hair straightener started the fire.But I think I'm partly at fault.
我没有告诉你 我最近放了新的卫生纸
You see,I didn't tell you,but...I had recently refilled the tissues.
那个太容易着火了
And so,let's face it,that's just kindling.
所以我应该来住乔伊家
So I think it's fair that I stay at Joey's.
不，菲比，都是我不好 而且我在这里好得很
No,no,no,this was my fault.Besides,I'm fine here.
好吧…钱德，莫妮卡在找你 是喔？
-Okay.Chandler,Monica's looking for you. -Really?
好像跟饼干屑有关
-She said something about crumbies.
不不不，我已经那么小心了
-No,no,no! I was so careful.
你一定要跟我换 莫妮卡快把我逼疯了
You have to switch with me. Monica is driving me crazy.
是的，小姐们都想住乔伊家
That's right. All the ladies want to stay at Joey's.
不要，我不想换 拜托啦，我在这里可以扔纸巾
No,I don't want to switch.Please! I can throw wet paper towels here!
在对面你可以对着水槽吃饼干
No,but at Monica's,you can eat cookies over the sink.
我知道，对不起 算了
I know. I'm sorry.All right,fine.
这个好像很好玩，湿嗒嗒的
This looks like so much fun. God,what a mess.
校规里真的有
Wow,it actually is in the handbook.
我不能和你约会 或是在研究室放电磁炉
I can't date you or have a hot plate in my office.
不敢相信我们居然不能再见面了
I can't believe we have to stop seeing each other.
不过谢谢你为我挺身而出 我好感动
For what it's worth,I did appreciate you standing up for me.That felt really nice.
我更喜欢你了
Kind of made me like you even more.
我知道，我也很喜欢你 但是我们不能交往
I know,I know. I really like you too. But we can't date.
校规明文禁止师生恋
It's against the rules. It's forbidden.
怎么了？
-Wow. -What?
光听你说校规禁止 就觉得好性感
Just hearing you describe it as "forbidden"...it's really hot.
真的？ 对
Really?Yeah.
不管有多性感，这都是错的
Well,I don't care how hot it is,it's wrong.
别再说了
-Stop it.
不，这是错的，这样很坏
-No,no. It's wrong.It's naughty.
这是禁忌
It's...taboo.
把书合起来
Shut the book.
再去弄个电磁炉吧
Hey. Let's also get a hot plate.
怎样啊？ 怎样？
-So? -So...?
今天是星期四，试镜结果如何
It's Thursday! How was the audition?
什么？星期一，一天，星期二，二天 星期三，三天，星期四…
It's.. Monday,one day. Tuesday,two day. Wednesday,what day..